[Music]
good morning everyone today i'm out
foraging for supplies and it is a crisp
cool autumn day
i absolutely love it it is the perfect
day at work on some new projects i have
in mind
in this video i thought i'd share some
ways that i manage my finances while
living really moving here definitely
affected how i spend money and i manage
it differently now
this video isn't meant to be advice as
we're all in different situations that i
will not compare or generalize but i
thought i'd share my personal story with
how my relationship with the more
economical side of life has evolved over
time
[Music]
so
as i talked about in a past video i will
link below i used to have a very anxious
relationship with money and at times i
still do though i've made a lot of
progress
i think it's worth admitting that
because despite what our salary is some
of us don't have the best relationship
with it
for example many university students
graduate with large debt and that can
impact your view of money
in my case experiencing extended times
without making enough to get by and
having to ask my family for support in
many situations
made me attach anxiety to the idea of
money in general thinking that if i only
had enough of it i would feel safe and
not need to worry so much
[Music]
when i finally moved got a new job and
began making enough to live comfortably
i still held on to these anxious
feelings associated with money
i would opt to save instead of spend it
at every opportunity sometimes to the
detriment of my health or safety
thankfully i have a wise father who
explained why i should never do that and
encourage me to make good choices and
invest in my future retirement even if
it was only a few dollars each month
[Music]
another reality check i had was when i
was living with my sister in her
apartment and one night she got
appendicitis
if she hadn't had health insurance she
would have been over fifteen thousand
dollars in debt simply to have the
surgery that would save her life
it was shocking and really made me
understand the importance of finding
ways to afford those costs if i possibly
could
consequently this led me to watch many
hours of youtube videos about financial
management and there is so much to learn
i'm amazed we aren't taught more about
it in school as it is so very useful
[Music]
i equated money with feeling safe as if
through it i could manage any unexpected
circumstances life threw at me
and it was very interesting to
transition into a stable situation
and realize that that wish to feel safe
didn't go away
because the safety i was looking for
went beyond affording groceries and
health insurance
i wanted the safety of a peaceful mind
as well a haven from intrusive thoughts
and worries
money wasn't going to resolve that
[Music]
that's something i've been thinking a
lot about this year especially as my
channel has grown i still find myself
afraid my life will change again
unexpectedly that my business will fail
or that i can't rely on my current
situation
i can't be sure things will work out how
i would like them to
there's no amount of hard work that can
guarantee it
and sometimes i convince myself that
everything will somehow fall apart
i've consequently realized that i
desperately want to find a way to assert
some control over my life
to somehow see into the future and know
i can handle anything
i also wish to have children and own a
home someday and i think that if i only
sacrifice enough and deprive myself of
enough in the present somehow i can make
that dream a reality but that isn't
always how things work
and the spiritual part of me knows deep
down that all that worrying is fruitless
well sometimes we need to sacrifice
something in the present to ensure the
future
when we do this all the time something
important is at risk for being lost
i'm still on a journey towards creating
a harmonious relationship between saving
and spending
for example i'm someone who greatly
values their home life and atmosphere so
i enjoy investing in my home with basic
skills i can transform thrifted
furniture and as you see in this video
create my own items
[Music]
i realized that being so far away from
malls and large retail outlets that i
don't really feel any urge to go
shopping
i'm amazed by how much less i buy or
want simply because i'm not surrounded
by shops
consequently when i visit the city it is
so exciting to stock up on any items i
need when it comes to food i shop in
bulk and store food in a freezer and can
save money that way
[Music]
by buying in bulk reducing waste
thrifting home items and using free
services such as the library i'm able to
invest in some hobbies that i deeply
enjoy
such as my craft supplies and of course
reading
in this way i'm now able to prepare to
own a home someday and for my future
family
it's amazing how just learning a little
about finances can help you transform
your relationship with it and make you
feel empowered and like you're making
progress towards your dreams
slowly but steadily
in my case i have to pair with a more
spiritual understanding that nothing
material can make me feel truly safe and
secure
it is something far deeper that can
answer that call there must be balance
in everything in giving and taking
spending and saving end today versus
tomorrow
[Music]
i hope you found this video somewhat
interesting i think it's always fruitful
to consider a relationship with more
material things and see how we can
improve it it is a fact of our lives
that we cannot really escape so i would
love to hear your experiences as well
wishing you a lovely day or night and i
will see you next week
[Music]
do
you